Contact

mohit.khanna2008@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mohit-khanna-8079a885 (LinkedIn) mohit2008.github.io/ (Portfolio) topmate.io/mkhanna (Personal) mentorcruise.com/mentor/mohitkhanna/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Machine Learning
Computer Vision
Software Engineering

Languages

Hindi (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Convolutional Neural Networks in TensorFlow

Feature Engineering for Machine Learning

Graph Analytics for Big Data
Natural Language Processing in
TensorFlow

Data Scientist With R Track

Mohit Khanna

Data Scientist @ Google | Machine Learning | Deep Learning | 1x AWS 3x GCP | connect @ topmate.io/mkhanna | mentor @ mentors.to/mohitkhanna

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Summary

Find me on Preplaced: https://visit.preplaced.in/2r4
Book a one on one session with me @ https://topmate.io/mkhanna

Want a mentor who can accelerate your transition into Data science field or help you target for roles at FAANG companies then do enrol for my mentorship program @ https://mentorcruise.com/mentor/mohitkhanna/

I am a Data Science, Machine Learning & Deep Learning Practitioner with a demonstrated experience in building real world data products.

I am currently working as a Data Scientist in the Google Maps org supporting the Information quality team by auto-moderating user generated content via counter abusive machine learning models to protect our surface from any form of abuse and vandalism and ensure publication of highest data quality on Maps. I also contribute to the model sustainability efforts which allows Google to run and operate Machine Learning models at scale and prevent them from becoming stale.

Some of my previous work includes building an:

- 1. Al model for faster drug discovery via an automated Al workflow
- 2. Improving the quality of photon imaging using self supervised image denoising with no access to ground truth.
- 3. Cell Detection for automatic localisation and classification of nuclei and microtubules in microscopic images.

SkillSet

Cloud Computing:

- -- AWS Certified Solution Architect
- -- GCP Certified Data Engineer
- -- GCP Certified Cloud Engineer
- -- GCP Certified Cloud Developer

Data Engineering:

- -- Exploratory Data Analysis
- -- Data Cleaning
- -- Data Preprocessing
- -- Feature Engineering
- -- Data Modelling
- -- Data Visualisation
- -- Data Mining
- -- ETL

Statistics:

- -- Descriptive
- -- Inferential
- -- Predictive
- -- Prescriptive
- -- Bayesian

Experimentation:

- -- Frequentist Approach
- -- Bayesian Approach (Multi Armed Bandit, Epsilon Greedy)

Database:

- -- No SQL
- -- SQL

Programming Language:

- -- Python
- -- Java
- -- SQL
- -- R

Modelling Techniques:

-- Statistical Modelling Testing

- --- Machine Learning (Supervised, Unsupervised, Self-supervised, Semi-Supervised)
- -- Deep Learning

Visualisation Tools:

- -- Matplotlib
- -- Tableau
- -- D3

Big Data frameworks:

- -- Spark
- -- Hadoop
- -- Hive
- -- Hbase
- -- Map Reduce

Data science libraries:

- -- Pandas
- -- Numpy
- -- Matplotlib
- -- Seaborn
- -- Scikit-learn
- -- Tensorflow
- -- Keras
- -- Scipy
- -- NLTK
- -- Gensim

Devops tools:

- -- Docker
- -- Git
- -- Chef

Experience

Google

Data Scientist

June 2021 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India

I am currently working as a Data Scientist in the Google Maps org supporting the Information quality team by auto-moderating user generated content via counter abusive machine learning models to protect our surface from any form of abuse and vandalism and ensure publication of highest data quality on Maps. I also contribute to the model sustainability efforts which allows Google to run and operate Machine Learning models at scale and prevent them from becoming stale.

MentorCruise

Data Science Mentor (mentors.to/mohitkhanna) December 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India

I mentor folks where I help them with learning and executing data science projects, build a career in data science, build data products, create ETL pipelines, build dashboards, interpret, deploy, maintain ML models in production. In addition to my monthly mentorship, i also offer one-off sessions for 1:1 calls, interview preparation, resume feedback.

LatentView Analytics

2 years 5 months

Assistant Manager@Data Science September 2020 - June 2021 (10 months)

Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India

Data Scientist

February 2019 - September 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Springboard

Data Science, AI &ML Mentor July 2019 - May 2020 (11 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

I mentored data science aspirants and enthusiasts across 2 offered tracks: Data Science career track and AI/ML career track.

Udacity

Independent Consultant for Machine Learning, NLP, Business Analytics, Data Analyst March 2019 - May 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

As a consultant to educational platforms, such as Udacity, I utilize my specialised knowledge in the field of Machine Learning and my strong communication skills to provide project reviews and other student support services.

Infosys

3 years 2 months

Technology Analyst(Data Science) at the Center Of Exellence October 2018 - January 2019 (4 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Senior System Engineer at the Center of Excellence at Infosys May 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

System Engineer

December 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 6 months)

I am working as a DevOps programmer to devlop some cool technologies like the Entitlement Server for Apple, Location-Based-Services for T-Mobile. The domain of technologies used is quite vast and almost every tool we use is Open-Source

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Masters of Computer Science in Data Science, Computer

Science · (2017 - 2019)

Udacity

Nanodegree, Deep Learning (2018 - 2018)

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University
Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Computer Engineering · (2011 - 2015)

Seth anandram jaipuria

High school, Science · (1999 - 2011)